Maybe one, maybe multiple.
I'm just going to just start a
transcription if that's okay. Yeah.
Um...
Yep, yep, that's fine.
So you've got table judges master,
which is your one row per person.
Table judges is 1 row per role.
Mhm.
So table judges links to table judges
master by the ID.
So you can have multiple rows in table
judges for the one person.
Now that can be roles that are still
active or it could be roles that they've
Mm-hmm.
been promoted from.
And it can even be provisional roles.
If we've been notified in advance that
they're going to be given this role,
then we can set up a provisional record
for them.
So would it cater to something like if a
judge is doing a DJ role in one code and
a DDJ role in another circuit,
something like that?
Yep, yep.
So you would have one.
Yeah, so, yeah, in that case,
they would have one row in judges master,
but two in table judges.
Yeah.
And the same for retirement as well,
things like that, right?
Uhh...
Yeah, yeah,
if they're sitting in retirement,
normally what you would have,
you would have the roles that they used
to be a salary judge in.
but then you would have a sitting in
retirement fee paid role which goes live
once.
The salaried rolls are marked as retired.
which is something,
there's an overnight routine that
Okay.
basically picks up and updates all the
roles and things like that based on
various dates in there.
Mmh.
The next one down is table judges user
links.
Now that is just if the judge has asked
for a login for JI,
we link their user ID to their actual
judge codes. Sorry, no,
it's their judge's master ID, I think.
so that they can only see their own data
on screen.
Information, OK,
so that's so that's mainly login
information, right?
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
Table judge types is just metadata,
gives us all the different judge types
and the relevant judge type IDs.
As is table judge statuses,
that's just metadata for what their
current status is. There's a column.
So such types will be things like if it's
a DJ,
DDJ or DJ and MC and things like that.
Circuit Judge, all the way up to, oh,
crikey,
lords and things like that who've got
high rolls. So yeah,
See, OK.
so that covers pretty much everything.
So status, that's all your active,
promoted, retired, deleted, deceased.
We have quite a number of statuses for
there. Judge circuits is metadata as well.
Now it's a bit confusing,
whereas in HMCTS we have
the regions around the country.
So there's one, two, three, 4,
I think six or seven regions.
For some reason, the judges still...
use circuits.
Now circuits were what regions used to be
called about 15 years ago.
Mm-hmm.
and actually it's probably longer than
that.
And they don't quite line up to regions.
So we have to have a list of the circuits
so that we know if we're talking about
circuits or regions that they're
completely different things.
Circuit George is still a thing, right?
Even though...
A...
Circuit judges, yeah, yeah, it's,
but if you're talking about judges
circuits,
then that is actually talking about the
Mhm.
area where they're employed.
Definitely.
Leadership judge types,
now there are some judges that are in
control of other judges to a certain
degree.
So that's just a metadata table to say
what leadership judge types we've got.
So I think there's things like the
Regional Family Judge,
the Regional Civil Judge,
the Regional Crane Judge.
It is just various different ones that
are there.
And table judge type promotion is
basically a table that gives us the
promotion paths available.
For each of the judge types,
and that's used more for when we're...
actually dealing with the judges within
the help desk applications.
If we want to promote them,
it will basically only allow us to give
them a valid promotion type.
Mhm.
Um...
So how do we use that? So promotion,
it's not clear in my head,
what role does it play in the system?
Right, well,
it's done through the help desk because a
judge can get promoted.
Say they're a district judge,
they could get promoted to a circuit
judge.
Yeah.
So, we get notified of that.
And it depends when we're notified.
Sometimes we're notified in advance
before the actual names of the judges
that have been promoted have been
See, OK.
published. So in that case,
we would actually create a new judges
master record and a new judge record,
and then we would merge the table judges
record.
Into the master judges record,
once they've been announced,
but it just allows,
it just allows the users to create
Can.
working patterns, that sort of thing.
So is it fair to say it's more of a
placeholder when the judge is actually
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Some regions don't do it in advance like
not promoted or it's not there yet? Okay.
that.
They actually tell us once the names have
been published.
And so the Vicky team basically would go
Mm.
into the help desk.
they'd go into the original judge's
record,
they can click a promote button and
they'll be given the options available
for a promotion and it just creates an
error record.
It's just to save them time more than
anything else.
And once you have the judge record in the
promotion,
that is then used for allocation so
people can actually use that judge and
assign work to that judge sitting there.
Yeah, they can actually do do things.
And once the judge is actually officially
announced, it's no longer secret,
then they get a new row and table judges,
I presume, link to the master.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, yeah,
linked to the original master so that we
can see, basically,
so that we can see the whole record of
that judge's career to a certain degree.
So how do you exclude it once the judge
is gone into the judges?
Because presumably the row in judge type
promotion is not valid anymore, right?
Yep.
So do you exclude it then on certain
basis?
It's just all done as part of the
overnight routines.
I'd have to go through all the code and
work out exactly what it's doing because
Yeah.
there's so many functions that happen in
the overnight routines. But yeah,
it does update all the judge records.
It basically,
if they come up to their retirement date,
it'll retire them.
If it's come up to the promotion date,
it sorts all the bits out that we need
done within there.
But there's no situation where we have a
row for the same judge in judges and in
judge type promotion because that's
contradictory.
Yeah, no, no, yeah, yeah, yeah,
nothing like that would ever happen.
Yep.
If we go to the...
Just trying to think which is going to be
the best one to go to next.
Bookings and sittings,
that's quite an easy one.
Mhm.
So bookings are for your fee pay judges,
sittings are for your salary judges.
Yeah.
So with sittings,
So that's table JI plan settings.
You have one row in there per salaried
judge per working day.
The user has an option to add rows for
non-working days because it might be that
a judge is sitting on a weekend or
something along those lines.
Likewise, if there's an absence,
then the row is marked as cancelled.
We never actually delete rows from Table
JI plan settings.
We just mark them as cancelled so that
we've got a full record there.
Mhm.
Um...
With bookings, it's slightly different.
So with your fee paid bookings,
we have table bookings and sorry,
table JI FP bookings and table JI FP
booking detail.
FP obviously standing for fee paid. Now,
Yeah.
the booking is a bit similar to the
judges master and the judges link.
The booking could be for a day, a week,
a fortnight. It could be for a month.
So we have all of the core details for
the booking in table JIFP bookings,
and then table JIFP booking detail will
have a row for each day within the
booking.
I see, OK, so that's more granular, right?
So it's so it could have one to many,
Yeah, yeah.
so one booking you have many records in
the booking detail.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it allows us to do a number of different
things in there as well.
So say the court decide they want to
cancel one day of a two week booking,
it allows us to do that without having to
cancel the whole booking and book it
again. So it is quite handy.
Yeah.
Booking types, actually,
I can't remember what that one actually
is. Let me just have a quick look.
I can bring up the booking type actual
table, because we'll have the.
That's right,
I've got SQL Developer open here,
Okay.
so seconds to...
Table chair.
King types.
It's quite handy, isn't it?
So I sort of gave my AI tooling this PDF
and said, make me a, you know,
data design diagram.
And it actually did a quite decent job
even segregating into different areas.
Yeah, yeah.
F.
That is brilliant, is. Ohh, right.
Yeah, there are different types.
So you've got your normal one,
which is a fee paid booking.
So this is just a metadata table.
OK.
Um...
But you can have things like,
if say they were called in on a weekend,
that's normally classed as an urgent
court business booking.
There's various other types of booking
that you can have there and they could
Okay.
potentially be paid different amounts
based on.
I see.
what type of booking it is.
And it also helps, again,
it goes back to what I was saying
yesterday about the fact that JI was
originally created as a data tool.
It was just to get its data.
Something, yeah.
We only basically gave the functionality
to get the users to use it because
They wouldn't have been happy just
putting information in.
Yeah.
So would that booking types also have
like what kind of fees applicable for
that booking type?
No,
that's actually linked elsewhere in one
of the tables that's shared elsewhere,
which is why it's one of the ones that I
OK.
haven't got in that list yet.
But because of course the fees change
See.
each year, they go up each year,
so we have to have records for all the
different types,
all the different judge types and
All of the different time periods that
they cover.
So who enters this data in terms of
different feed structures?
Is that the JI users, RSU users, whatever?
No, no, that comes down to me.
That's part of my role.
Okay.
I have finance or judicial office,
let me know.
Okay, so there's a lot,
so there's an RFC or something like that
and you set up that judge behind the
scenes.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
To a certain degree we do get Vicky's
team to do stuff as well.
The ones that I've trained up is part of
Mhm.
the reason we're having the help desk
apps.
Basically what I try and do is put things
in there that I think
if I can do everything programmatically
and safely do it programmatically,
I will put a page in there for them to
use and just keep an eye on it myself.
See you.
which I've had no choice,
basically I've had to do that since we
dropped down from three people to just me.
Mm.
Um...
Do, do, do, do, do.
How do you get your application,
your leave approved? I'm wondering.
Ha ha ha!
What do you do to get that approved?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's basically...
They do just pretty much approve anything
I ask for. Obviously,
Mm.
if I was to ask for a month off,
I don't think that would be approved.
Mmh.
But I have had a fortnight before now,
but on the whole,
I do just take weeks or less. We actually,
there's a system on all of our
applications we call Message of the Day.
which just allows us to put notification
messages up.
And we've actually started in the last 12
months putting messages up to say that
there's no second line support for a week
or very limited second line support.
Mhm.
There are
a couple of people that can do things.
And the guy I mentioned yesterday that's
been promoted in a dire emergency,
he could be called back,
but it's not something that anybody
really particularly wants to do.
Okay.
Plus also is the fact he's not done
anything for so long. So yeah,
I think it's just accepted now that
Yeah.
There's just times when we're not going
to have second-line support.
Mhm.
Thankfully, up until now,
we've never had any critical problems.
Not like this morning.
Yeah.
That, yeah.
This week, sir.
Yeah, it's all good fun.
Table JIFP cancillors.
Think, let me just quickly check.
I think that's just used for a list of
values. Yes,
that is to say who's cancelled a booking.
Now this goes back to what was said
yesterday about if it's cancelled last
minute.
the fee paid judges can actually still
claim their fee.
So when a booking is cancelled,
we do actually ask whether it was the
Mm.
judge,
the local office or the judicial team
that cancelled it.
Because obviously if it was the judge,
then they're not entitled to that payment.
It's one of those things that really goes
back to when we were actually paying the
cancelled or the late cancellations
Mm.
through the system,
but it's the sort of thing that JFEPs do
look at to see who actually cancelled it.
So if I had like a booking for a week,
you would have 5 rooms in the booking
Yeah.
detail for each day and then one of them
gets cancelled,
Yeah.
Yep.
you'll have one row in the cancellers.
Yeah.
So, cancelers, I mean that.
Oh, oh, sorry, sorry, no, no,
the counsellor is just data that's used
for an LOV.
What do you mean by LOV?
List of values.
Okay,
so the people who are allowed to cancel
or...
Yeah, yeah.
Or whether it was judge or it was someone
else cancelling that booking, I see.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
But that cancellation detail where I
presume will stay in the booking detail,
right?
That will be in the booking detail. Yeah,
we will.
We've got various columns in there that
hold all sorts of information about the
cancellation,
even the date that the e-mail was sent to
the judge saying it was cancelled.
So it's almost like a reference data kind
of thing.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thanks.
Um...
Just keep doing the smaller blocks first.
Let's come across to audit and
cross-cutting.
Yeah.
Right,
so table JI changes and table JI change
types, we don't really use it as much now.
This was something we tried to build in
to allow us to build up a full history of
what was happening. So table JI changes,
basically whenever any change was made to
any of the
the key tables, we would have a change ID.
And then this would detail what the
Okay.
previous values were based on the values
that have been amended. Unfortunately,
we had it there when we first went live,
but because we had to make changes so
quickly,
it's one of those things that dropped a
bit by
By the side.
It's been huge within the first month
itself, isn't it?
It was horrendous. Yeah,
that was another reason why we sort of
Yeah.
decided, no,
it was a nice idea to be able to have a
full audit history.
But it just didn't really work.
So they're semi-obsolete.
We just keep them there because there are
Mm.
certain times when they do.
Still log something.
Still, OK.
and table JI restricted ITIN users that
stands for.
So most users can only see the current
financial year.
Mm.
in their data, because again,
it all comes back to people knowing
things in advance.
So when they're setting up new working
patterns for the next financial year,
that's all supposed to be kept secret
until each judge has been personally
informed.
So what we do, we have this table,
JI restricted ITIN users,
which basically just gives us IDs of
users that are allowed to view future
itineraries. Obviously,
when it comes to sort of January,
February,
that gets quite full of people because...
by that time people do need to see the
next financial year.
But one of my 1st of April tasks is to
actually wipe all of that table apart
from RSU users.
And we're talking about actual users here,
not user types, right?
Set.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. So yeah,
it ranges this time of year.
There's probably only about 50 rows in
there. But come, well, say March time,
there can be pretty much every user in
there.
Yeah.
It's just saying,
it's something that we don't actually
deal with ourselves.
That's something the RSU has a user that
can actually set that up and add people
to it. So that just covers that.
Yeah,
so RSU should be able to do that because
they are actually doing their activity
right.
So it's the code users who should not be
able to access that before the time.
Yeah.
Mm.
Yeah.
Um, but yeah,
it's they need to be in there to be.
It's extremely,
extremely optimistic to be able to
predict five years.
Yes, yeah. Yeah, to be perfectly honest,
I think even going two years in advance
would be pushing it.
And particularly when things happen like
Yeah.
this year where they've been told that
they can basically sit as many days as
they want to rather than being restricted
like they have in the past.
So if anyone had pre-done this year,
they've probably had to go back and do it
See.
all again.
So what happens to sitting days, right,
when they say unlimited?
So what do they do with the sitting days?
They just sort of ignore it or?
Yeah,
basically we have the profiles for the
number of sitting days,
but if they go over their profiles,
it doesn't really matter.
That's another return that I'm working on
Mhm.
at the moment within OPT data itself,
because everyone's set their profiles,
Okay.
but they've got it wrong.
So I'm having to unverify literally, well,
near enough every location,
which is great fun.
It's not boring at all.
Mhm.
Yeah, I believe you.
Yeah.
Okay, an absence and cover workflow.
So ABSO B and ABSO B detail,
that's much the same as bookings and
booking detail. So you have your absences.
The ABSO B is actually absences and
official business.
Okay.
So you have an absence,
which could be a day, it could be a week,
it could be a year.
So you have one row for the whole absence
in table JI, abs OB,
and then an individual row per day in the
detail table.
Mhm.
Exactly the same reasons as bookings,
it allows you to change one day without
having to cancel the whole absence.
Yeah.
Um...
Cats types.
So it's categories, types,
vacancy options.
And vacancy council reasons,
they're all used for list of values,
so they're just standing data. They do,
we do get, yeah, yeah,
Reference data.
we do get occasional rows added or rows
taken away,
Yeah.
but they all have an in-use column in
them, so it's easy to.
To mark something as not available.
Uh...
Vacancy and vacancies groups,
that's a bit like all these others again.
So vacancies is actually the detail table,
whereas vacancy groups is the
overall table.
So this is when there's been an absence
or there is going to be an absence and
they've said they want to create a
vacancy for it.
So you would have vacancy groups,
there'd be a one row in there which
covers the whole period of the vacancy.
And then one row in vacancies per day of
the vacancy.
Typically,
we've not followed the same naming format
Yeah.
there.
I think this was going back to when we
initially created it all.
There was one of us doing one bit,
one of us doing another,
and we hadn't sort of come to a
conclusion what the best naming
conventions were.
Yeah, I was going to get pedantic on that,
but I think I hear you reading.
Yeah, yeah.
It's probably one of the first steps it
was probably you created and then
Yeah.
realized,
let's stick with the detailed pattern.
Yeah, yeah, it makes more sense.
And even now I regularly forget about
vacancy groups if I'm searching for a
problem or something like that,
because it just doesn't follow the flow
of all the other tables.
Yeah, no,
I think this thing and underscore detail
For.
is much more intuitive and.
Yeah, it is obvious.
It is obvious what we got there. Right,
Yeah, yeah.
let's have a look at the reference data.
Columns, types, cats, sitting durations.
There he is, extra non-working days.
Actual.
Working day link.
Planned working day links.
JTSDO.
Although that'll be sitting day links.
I'm not quite sure what JT links is.
It's just...
UIA.
Maybe I'm having to have you remember
things which probably are not used
Well,
the problem is there's some of these
anymore.
tables that literally you just never go
to. Let's see what this...
Yeah.
That was UA.
Got to get myself a new pair of computer
glasses.
Ahh, right, yeah,
so that that bottom one is saying what's..
.
Judge types.
People of each user type can access.
It's.
So it's a bit like we were discussing
yesterday,
whereas the courts can see district
judges,
but can't normally see circuit judges.
So that's the table that allows for that.
Yeah.
And then, so...
Work patterns.
See.
Bert pattern detail.
Similar sort of thing when our work
patterns can be daily, weekly, monthly,
two weekly, three weekly, so...
Basically the same sort of thing again,
you have one row in the work pattern and
then one row per day in the work pattern
in the detail.
Jurisdictional split.
So each judge can be split technically
between civil, family, crime,
and I think there's a few other things as
well. So we keep a record there.
This is based on judge role.
So table judges,
so I think it's linked to the judge code
and that just tells us what the split is
per year or I think it's got a start date
and an end date so it can be any time
during the year it can change.
So this is where the user is going in and
saying he's going to sit 40% family,
30% civil, things like that. Okay.
Yeah, yeah.
Judge Juris.
Uhh...
Says it, just judge.
It again,
like a reference data for the
jurisdictions or something.
It, it looks like it, yeah, and just...
Oh yes,
so that literally has just got three rows
in it, crime, civil and family.
So that is a reference data table.
Mhm.
Ticket types is another reference data
table which basically says all of the
different ticket types that are available
to a judge and there's quite a lot of
them.
Whereas judges links the tickets type to
the judge.
So that's the one that tells us what
Tickets the judge has actually got.
Mhm.
Judge courts link,
that's what courts a judge can sit at.
And basically,
that's mostly used for when judges are
shared.
So you can share a judge between courts,
Okay.
you can share a judge between regions.
And it's all done within JI itself.
They set up a sharing link.
and that will then populate that table.
So it allows us to say, oh yeah,
that judge can work at that court.
Judge fee rates,
so that's the one that I was mentioning
earlier.
So sorry, so on the link one,
so that will also have information on
Yeah.
which area it is actually shared with.
Yeah,
it is actually broken down to court IDs.
So each court,
so if we say we're sharing it with,
Okay.
sharing a Southeast judge with Northwest
Region,
there would be a row per court in
Northwest Region.
Okay,
so is there a concept of region in the
system or is it just quotes and the
region is sort of?
We, on the whole,
it is just done by courts.
We don't really do things by region
because it's simpler that way.
I can.
So how do you how do you work out which
code belongs to which region?
Right, each user has got.
as part of their user record, they have,
I can't remember what we call it,
it's like a location set up for them,
which lists all of the courts that they
Yeah, location.
can access.
With actually joining courts to region,
I see.
I've not actually,
this is one of the shared tables that I
got.
put in here. We have table courts,
which details all of the information on
the courts. That links to table areas,
which is basically now known as,
they're now known as clusters.
So you have so many courts within an area.
Yeah.
And then that links to table regions,
which gives us the regions.
So we just do the links there.
OK.
We just share the tables.
Yeah,
so fee rates basically is telling us for
each judge type. Oh, yeah, go on.
I just wanted to understand because I
think it's probably,
it's too many things in there,
packed in there.
Yeah.
So if I were to share a judge with
another region,
I would work out which courts this judge
is allowed to sit in and then create a
rule for each one of those in the links.
Yeah,
the system actually does it automatically.
So yeah, yeah.
So the user has a choice.
They can either share it with just
specified courts,
they can share it with an area or a
cluster,
or they can share it with a region.
And as soon as they click the button,
if they've chosen region,
It will put a row in per court within the
region.
The code.
But the user is themselves selecting the
region, right?
Yeah, the user would,
the user who's creating the sharing
agreement would select,
they've got two select boxes.
So the first one is saying whether they
want to do courts, areas,
clusters or regions.
And then the second one,
which populates based on the first one,
we'll then give them a list to pick from
of what they've got there.
So as far as they're concerned,
they're just saying that anyone on X
region can access it,
whereby as far as the system is concerned,
Mmh.
we put a row in there for each court
within that region.
OK, so, so where do you find out the, uh,
you know,
relationship between regions and and
codes?
That's all done within the package
function and it does the link between
table cores,
table areas and table regions.
Yeah, I mean,
where is the data stored in here, which,
So it.
which?
which table has the linkage between the
region and the code.
We haven't actually got that here because
that's a set of tables that are shared
between all of the OPT apps.
These is a set of other tables that we
I see.
need to copy in there.
The problem is working out how many of
the shared tables and shared packages are
actually being used.
Yeah.
It's just trying to find them all.
Okay.
Yep, so fee rates,
that just is the one that I manually
populate each year when the fees go up
for the fee paid judges.
There's a row in there per judge type or
per fee paid judge type.
and per time period,
which does tend to be a financial year.
And that.
Yeah.
And it ties to the judges, right?
Because at different rules,
they may have different fees.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
Judges annual leave,
we have one row in there per judges
master ID for salaried judges only.
It just basically, again,
it's the overnight routines.
They calculate all the various values
needed to work out judges annual leave.
Mhm.
It was just done to speed things up.
So that's populated every night and then
updated as users make changes.
Part of the bookings and sittings change
code will actually update
Cheat table judges annual leave.
And then the two stats tables are
probably the key tables as far as we're
concerned.
Monthly stats is actually a new one.
It's only come into operation in the last
year,
whereby we're trying to put a row in.
Preach.
judges master ID saying how many days the
judges sat in that month,
all the different jurisdictions,
all the different types of sitting they
could have done and also we're populating
the absences in there.
So that's just being used for
one of our dashboards.
one of our Power BI dashboards.
And that's not reflect,
and that does not reflect the role, right?
It's like whatever they were doing,
whether they are paying,
Yeah.
doing DDJ role or DJ role,
it doesn't matter.
Yep, yep, yeah, whatever role,
we're just making sure that we know.
how many days basically that judge has
sat for us or done other things.
Table judges booking stats,
that is a similar sort of thing. Again,
it's used for one of the Power BI
dashboards.
It just gives information on the bookings.
It doesn't include absences.
And also, that is done per judge role.
So, if a judge is a...
DJ and a recorder,
there'd be one row in there for each of
those two roles.
So you mentioned Power BI dashboards.
How do you transport this data to that
system?
A very complex way.
We have a schema on the live server
Mhm.
called table, sorry, table,
a schema called optlive underscore RO,
which is a read-only version of a number
of the tables.
Mhm.
and then there's an overnight routine
that then transfers the current content
of these tables from up live reader only
over to our BI server.
And then that from there,
it gets pulled into SDP or wherever it
Okay.
needs to be used.
Up live read only is used for other
things as well.
If I'm training up a new person,
I don't give them access to up live
straight away.
I give them access to up live read only
and get them to do scripts,
which I can then cheque and I will
actually run the scripts for them.
And also it's used by the dashboard teams
to just quickly have a look at some of
the data.
Yeah,
but we are still within the confines of
OPT system.
It's not leaving OPT system per se.
It is when it goes from read-only over to
the BI server.
Okay, so how does that connexion work?
How do you,
because that presumably is in the cloud,
right?
It.
No, no, believe it or not,
that is another server that we've
Yeah.
basically got 4 servers and they've all
got database links on them.
Okay.
So you've got the two dev servers for
want of a better name.
So there's the JI dev server, which that
contains the development schema that I
use.
It contains the training schema and a
test schema.
Mhm.
And then the BI Dev server is just
basically a copy of the BI server,
but it allows them to test things out
before they change things on there.
And then we've got, we call them live,
so it's Ops Live and BI Live,
Okay.
but they're basically the prod servers.
So when I say OPT, I mean,
it's still within the scope of that.
When you say Power BI,
we still Power BI within the OPT world.
Oh yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yes, yeah, yeah, yeah,
is we just move it onto a different
Okay.
server for use with Power BI.
Yeah,
so it's not Power BI like the enterprise
where other reports are running at.
This is different, this is specific to JI.
Yeah, yeah, as far as I'm aware.
Mm.
Um...
I think that's about it, isn't that,
for those?
Mhm.
I think we done pretty well going through
them.
Yeah.
So in terms of I think the other other
thing I was looking at was...
You know,
to help me understand a little bit more
about the application,
I think it'll be really helpful because I
can use the AI,
like just the way I've generated this.
Yeah.
I can use AI tooling to actually generate
documentation of the back of your
artifacts.
So if you're able to export the
Yeah.
application and export any...
You know, schema, and you know,
maybe put it in.
Yeah, if I...
I don't know what approvals you said you
needed some approvals to put in.
Yeah,
I'm literally just waiting for my manager
to get back to me saying...
Yes, go ahead. Let me,
let me just really share my screen.
I'll show you.
Yeah.
Where I am.
Sorry,
this is the problem when you've got 3
screens,
is making sure you're sharing the right
one.
Absolutely.
Has that come up yet?
Yeah, yeah, I can see it, yeah.
Yeah, yeah,
I've actually been doing a bit on here
today, so this is the...
Repo that I'm working on at the moment,
so...
I've got the most, or one of the most,
actually that's not the most recent,
I'll have to put the main one in there.
So that's the actual app exports.
Mm.
Okay.
We've got all the JI packages in there.
Mhm.
I didn't know if you wanted the body as
well as the spec,
so I've given you both for each one.
Yeah, no, that's good.
See to sort of explain the rationale,
right?
Cap.
It's not so much because the new system
will look and feel quite different, right?
Yeah.
It's not a like replacement.
It's going to be more API driven with
database, but it's not going to be,
you know, database driven system,
Yeah.
so to speak.
So the purpose of getting this is to
actually, you know,
to build as clear a picture of.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
That's the main, you know,
reason just to explain it.
Yeah, it's the problem I've got,
so we got everything in here nearly. Well,
I haven't got all the tables in there yet.
I only started doing that today.
Mhm.
But again,
it's going to be the shared things,
identifying the shared things that are
going to take me the time.
Yeah.
And I try to keep this open.
during the day,
because if I've got some long running
code going or something,
I can quickly start copying a few bits
across to it. But yeah, I'm not far off.
I literally,
as soon as I get the authority,
I'll give you the access to it.
Mm.
I don't see what the problem is.
It's not secret.
The I don't think anybody.
Yeah, and there's no data in it, right?
There's no data in it.
No, no, no, no, there's, yeah,
you're not going to see anything that
shouldn't be seen. It's, yeah,
it annoys me more than anything else that
Yeah.
they don't just say yes straight away,
but I know what they're like.
But if it comes to it,
I will make the decision myself if they
don't come up with a...
Yeah, no, no, I don't want to rush you,
so I think if you're waiting for
Yeah, yeah.
something, let's do it the proper way.
Yeah, but at the end of the day,
it would be quite nice if I've got
everything in the repo first as well.
But what I'm going to do,
Yeah.
any shared packages,
any shared procedures, things like that,
I will separate them out within the repo.
So you can see those.
So when you say, when you say shared,
what exactly, who are you sharing it with?
Yeah.
What exactly do you mean by shared?
It's shared with other applications
within the OPT ecosystem. So if I.
Within open.
You mean with code planner and things
like that?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, so, well,
the perfect example is the tables.
Yeah.
So, here's table courts,
which is used all over the place.
Mm.
So basically,
I can show you the data in this because
none of this is secret.
So this basically all of the courts,
all of the tribunals, each of them have
an ID, each of them have a court type.
They have a lot of data in here that's
not used anymore.
But you can see you have area ID,
Mhm.
OCJB area ID,
there's various other area IDs as well,
but the main one is the area ID.
So that then
Would link to table areas.
So if we say area ID 34,
which court is that? Oh,
it's a closed one. Let's go Aberystwyth,
which is also 34.
So then we have table areas.
One of my favourite places I bussed with,
I've been there a few times.
I love Wells.
Nice and quiet up there.
Yeah,
it's just a simple cross over the bridge
for me. It's my father-in-law has got...
A little cottage that his parents used to
live in,
in a tiny little village called
Bettisquerfel Goch in North Wales,
Mhm.
is not far from Snowdon actually,
but it's just great going out there,
it's so peaceful.
Yeah.
So anyway, so there's our areas.
And so this is area ID 34,
which is part of region ID 7.
O, if we then go to Regions.
So region ID, sorry, region ID 7.
Is the last row, so it's Wells.
So that's just literally how we can then
track back from Wales.
We can go to all of the areas within
Wales and then go to all the courts in
Wales or vice versa.
Mmh.
But if I just quickly show you...
How many tables have we got in here?
There's quite a few to have to go through.
Some of them are obviously not going to
be used for...
Mm.
shared tables,
but I've never even actually bothered to
count how many we've got there,
but there's quite a few.
Likewise with packages.
Mm.
Yeah.
We've got a number of packages,
and there can be...
up to about 20,
000 rows of code in each package.
Mmh.
So, it's yeah,
just trying to work through and find out.
What is actually linked can be a
nightmare.
Yeah.
It's a lot difficult when the business
logic is embedded in the database code,
isn't it? It's a...
HeHis.
It's a lot difficult to change and things
are quite brittle, isn't it?
Yeah, it's it is it makes my life of hell,
it really does, but that's.
It works.
Part of the fun of it is it gives me a
challenge.
Yeah.
I'd rather be challenged at work than
board, so...
Yeah.
So just one question for you on this.
I think that's really helpful.
Yeah.
So because obviously a lot of...
the new system that we build,
we will get the judicial information from
judicial office, you know,
JOH through JOH integration.
Yeah.
Is there anything you can think of which
is mastered within JI,
which will not be available in, you know,
the JOH data?
I'm not sure if the fee rates would be in
there because that's finance.
Yeah.
So...
Mind you,
presumably you could link to JFEPS anyhow,
as well as Judicial Office.
So, you might be able to get it that way.
Um...
The tickets, as...
Rachel won that yesterday was saying.
For some regions,
they like to do the tickets themselves,
but they should be in the judicial office
system.
Mm.
And certainly the way JI is at the moment,
tickets aren't critical.
Yeah.
We don't actually link tickets to booking
types. It was always the plan,
but we were a little bit concerned that
potentially a judge might have to say
something they're technically not
ticketed for.
So, we never actually put that link in.
Yeah, a lot of the other stuff.
I mean, you could, yeah, so this is the,
let me just share my screen so you know
Yeah.
that. So this is the data from,
this is essentially the judicial office
holders data, right?
So if we look at data model,
Yeah.
so you can see you have people,
you have judiciary roles,
you have the authorizations,
the appointments.
base location, roles.
So as far as I can think of.
We can get this data from this office and
maintain it as a master list within the
Yeah.
new system.
But the local users of that system should
be able to add their own information if
they like.
Yeah,
so literally about the only thing that I
would say that definitely isn't there is
going to be the sharing agreements.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, yeah.
Because that's driven by local,
almost local business processes, isn't it?
Um...
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Everything else I think,
as long as you can get the fee rates from
JFEPS,
which I don't think would be a problem,
Yeah.
As far as I can think, everything else,
because you've got all the contact
details there.
You got your tickets, you got...
Because right now they actually send you
an e-mail and you add the fee for that
judge, right?
So if you build a screen for a finance
user specifically to be able to, you know,
adjust those fees,
Yeah, yeah.
then they can add whatever they want.
Yeah, yeah, it's.
Something I've never 100% trusted them
with,
so it's something that I need to do once
a year,
so it's not something that I've been
particularly bothered about. It's...
Yeah, yeah, I mean,
they are they're the ones paying,
so they better make it right.
Yeah, yeah. Yeah,
I've often wondered about setting myself
up a fee paid judge profile and putting a
load of sittings in.
That's the scary thing.
I've actually got the access that I could
Yeah.
do that,
but I think I'd get caught quickly enough.
Well, who's monitoring your work?
Yeah, thankfully,
because the way JFEPs work,
Mhm.
they would soon identify that there was
something not quite right.
I was just going to show you like some of
the data that they have,
so some of the endpoints that they have.
So for example, they have these.
Mm.
And points for people.
Leavers, people and people ID,
and I think it was.
Brilliant.
appointments they have, authorizations,
judicial rules, things like that.
Ohh, God, I...
And then you also have,
and then you also have reference data,
Of it.
which is, you know,
specifically around reference data.
Yeah.
I wish I had access to that,
make my life a lot easier.
Yeah, I know, I know it's a...
Ha ha ha.
It's when you see this, you know,
open systems and when you think back, oh,
Yeah.
I had to make a system which did not have
access to any of this, you know,
Yeah.
you're having to duplicate all this
information. It's a, but you know, just.
Yeah,
and it's easy enough to convert JSON to
something that I can use, so...
I'm not even thinking of, you know,
redoing the scheme.
I can just put in JOH in front and just,
you know,
Yeah.
put populated on my side and then have my
own tables layered on top to actually do
whatever specific I want to do,
but you know,
Veridian.
it's hindsight is a beautiful thing,
isn't it? So it's...
Yeah, yeah, it's, well,
to be perfectly honest,
when we first built JI,
the judicial system,
there was never any thought that anybody
else would ever see the data there.
Mm.
Yeah.
Also,
I think the other thing I was thinking
was like...
Things come into my mind and then just
slip away.
Yeah.
I always put that down to old age myself.
Yeah.
Yeah, or maybe I'm getting to that age.
No,
Yeah.
I was thinking of the six thing which
Rachel mentioned yesterday because I was
thinking that I could make the whole
thing automated if they are getting their
absences recorded in upstream.
But it looks like they don't send all the
Yeah.
absences because it's a business,
which makes sense once Rachel explained
No.
it because.
Once they've been onboarded as a judge,
right?
Makes sense that whatever code they're
working on, I assume they're working with,
they're telling them when they are going
on leave, and I still don't understand,
Yeah.
like,
if it is if it's a salary judge and you
go above your holiday, who actually,
you know, sort of tells them off.
Yeah, we actually have a balance on JI,
so it should be monitored.
And there's a carry forward system,
because obviously if they don't use all
Mhm.
of their leave that's available,
then they can carry forward days,
Yeah.
but they are allowed to carry forward
negative days as well.
that they have to get permission from
their presiding judge,
Mhm.
so the judge that's in charge of them all.
But yeah, yeah, nobody technically...
Yeah.
So this is the thing which makes me a
little bit a little bit nervous because
you know the concept of system of record,
right?
Yeah.
Because then JI in a sense becomes a
system of record for their holidays.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah, is is.
Do you see what I mean?
Whereas it is not supposed to be the
system of record for a judge's holidays,
you know,
No.
it's completely sort of different.
No, there's loads of things that J.I.
has become.
Mm.
that was never envisaged.
But at the end of the day,
it was the only way that we could sort it
all out.
What makes it even more confusing is the
fact that judges don't have an annual
leave entitlement.
Mm.
their contract is to sit so many days per
year.
So their actual annual leave allowance is
different every year.
S.
It only alternates by a day or two,
but we just call it annual leave because
See, OK.
that's what everyone calls it.
Technically it's a non-sitting day.
I see.
But yeah, that
It makes it all the more difficult to do
all the calculations and everything on it,
and I did go through a phase about three
or four years ago where...
Everything, well,
say 90% of everything that came through
to second line was because a judge
thought that their leave was incorrect,
their balance.
Yeah.
and I've got better things to spend my
time on than to prove that their balance
Yeah.
is correct. But as it was,
we seem to have gone past that.
It's very rare that I get a leave query
now.
It's very difficult to challenge a judge
when you hit with that, isn't it?
You almost need to double cheque your
work and then go back and say, no,
Yeah,
it is the problem is as well as the fact
you're wrong.
that HMCTS don't manage the judges.
Yeah.
So it's not as if I can particularly go
to a higher judge and say,
have a word with him,
which is what I can do with our other
Yeah.
users. As it is,
I have got some very good friends that
are judges in different parts of the
country.
Mm.
So I am quite lucky I can actually go.
Yeah.
To people.
Yeah, I did. So,
I did actually send a query to the
judicial office.
I'm talking to one of the architects in
Yeah.
that in that team, and you know,
asking what absence is information,
and he mentioned that you know the
absence is information is there in JHR,
but currently it's not exposed to the
eLinks. ELinks is the mechanism APIs,
Yeah.
but talking to Rachel yesterday.
As you mentioned, right,
it's only the sick days that they are
Yeah, yeah.
getting reported.
So I was just wondering why if they're
Yeah.
going on leave, like even if, you know,
their sitting days are established.
Yeah.
Why would they not inform the HR that we
are I'm going to be on view for?
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
because technically I would say that
they're probably the ones that should be
monitoring leave balances. But yeah,
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
it would make sense.
I suppose it's just historical.
Mm.
And the thing is as well,
you're going to have other absences types,
the classic ones, judicial college,
because they will have their own system,
Mm.
which is completely separate from the
judicial office system.
I see.
So, to find out whether...
So,
where does judicial college fit into all
this? So,
I'm completely new to MOJ sort of thing.
Well, yes,
so they're the ones that they will get
the judges trained up to be judges.
And so we have absences for judicial
I see.
college. Now,
the problem is they could either be a
delegate on a course or they could be the
trainer.
Mm.
So you have to keep records of both of
those.
And that's the sort of thing that the
judicial office might like to know that a
Yeah.
certain judge is a trainer,
but they're not concerned at all about
how many days training they do each year.
So I think I saw it in one of Rachel's
videos that there was sort of the dotted
An.
thingy in the square where this,
so you have two judges in that thing,
Yeah.
isn't it?
One is a trainer and one is the actual
Yeah, and when the trainee, yeah, is is.
being trained.
It's one of those unfortunate things with
JI.
There's so many little oddities like that
that you need to be able to keep a track
Mm.
of.
And I think this goes back to why before
JI, each region did things their own way.
Because a small region like
Mm.
Say, Wells.
they could quite easily do things
literally with a calendar and a piece of
Yeah.
paper. Whereas someone like Southeast,
actually I was quite surprised because I
would have always thought that Southeast
would have had some form of database
Mmh.
going because there were a couple of
regions that had access databases.
But what Southeast had
Was.
Spreadsheet for each charge.
Mm.
Um...
Well, that explains the backlog, isn't it?
Oh,
it was just horrendous when we first got
there. And trying to get them trained up,
I remember.
We spent about two months doing training,
as it was,
and for Southeast we had to spend a week
actually in their office with them.
So how did you get the users to move from
the Excel sheet into using the new system?
Because it must have been a hassle to,
you know, the...
We've got, yeah,
we got buy-in by management at quite a
high level, at the regional level. They
Yeah.
suddenly saw the benefits.
We were able to prove that there were
Yeah.
massive benefits.
Yeah.
And yes,
so basically in the end of the day,
they were told they had to take it on.
There was a lot of moaning.
Yeah.
I moan a lot about Southeast because they
were the biggest moaners right at the
beginning and they've been the bane of my
life ever since. But yeah,
Mm.
it was hard work at first.
Yeah,
because we had a session with one of the
tribunals today, SSCS,
and I think one of the challenges I can
see,
because they are already working with
quite fragmented systems,
because they're working in one system,
Yeah.
and then they've migrated to another
system for listings,
and that system also is not able to
support all the...
You know, SSCS areas,
so they're having to manage two systems.
Yeah.
So, when we are further, you know,
dividing the systems on functional basis,
you know,
we need to make sure we have all areas
covered,
and that's because there are so many
different systems being built.
On the premise that we will integrate
properly, and if some it's in.
Yeah.
Tribunals are a nightmare. They really,
really are.
Mhm.
And you've got things that you might have
a tribunal judge that spends most of his
time as a circuit judge.
Ah, okay.
And there is, which should be,
this is part of the reason why we have
always tried to get everything onto a
single system.
Mm.
Because it would make controlling judges
as people a lot easier. But
Mhm.
with JI written the way it was,
it would have just been far too much work,
particularly again because it's just dang
to me.
Yeah,
and if you have all the business logic in,
you know, database screens structure,
it makes it so hard to actually test,
Yeah.
make sure you haven't broken anything,
so the testing is that much harder.
Yeah, yeah.
Whereas if you have those logic sitting
in a higher level construct like a Java
Yeah, it.
program,
it makes it testing a little bit easier.
Yeah, yeah.
I used to do a lot of my testing on
Firefox.
We had Selenium and Molybdenum plugins in
Mhm.
there that automated it all for us.
But of course, we then moved away.
I see that.
We can't use Firefox anymore. So yeah, I
Ahh.
Actually,
last year I created a unit testing suite
that I'm just populating at the moment.
So, but again,
Mhm.
it's one of those things is finding the
time to do it is.
Okay.
Yeah,
you can use a lot of the AI tooling to
actually create scripts. So you can,
for example, use Playwright,
Yeah.
because that will actually use an
internal engine, like a browser, you know,
Yeah.
a headless engine.
So as long as you have that,
Ohh.
you can actually run those tests locally.
Ohh.
Yeah,
because I've used ChatGPT to do a lot of
stuff for me,
but it hasn't got that kind of capability.
Mhm.
I might have to look into that.
No, no, so you can, I think,
playwright is one such thing,
so you can look at maybe playwright and...
Yeah.
I think the constraint would be that what
you can actually install on the on the
system,
because you can you can use the AI to
It is so.
actually build you the scripts,
then get those scripts and actually run
Yeah.
it in the PowerShell or something like
that and see, you know,
where you get stuck with the permissions.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it's just one of those little projects
I've had that I don't think I'll ever get
it finished. Well,
Mm.
hopefully you'll get the new system built
and there'll be no problems and I can
Yeah.
retire.
One step at a time, it's a...
Yeah, we'll get there.
We'll get there eventually.
Right, so I think that's...
I mean,
you're already carrying on with that
GitHub stuff, so really, you know,
you've gone to the tables with me,
Yeah.
so that's really helpful. Thanks for that.
I will spend some more time, and you know,
Yeah.
if I have more questions,
I'll put maybe an hour again with you,
maybe in a week's time or two weeks' time,
if that's okay.
Yeah, yeah, that's fine. Well,
I'm sure once I eventually share the
GitHub repo with you,
there's going to be loads of questions
then.
Yeah,
one thing I would really like to do is
actually once I have tribunals understood
a little bit and once I have a rough
level, rough idea of the design,
I would like to maybe, you know,
Yeah.
run you through it so you can pick holes
in it from, you know,
Yeah.
a conceptual perspective.
Yeah, yeah.
So I can show you some of the stuff which
I'm doing.
If it's there.
Yeah, so you can see, for example,
you know, so this new system,
we're calling it as RAM Resource
Allocation Manager.
So you have like users interacting with
the system,
Yeah.
then you have data coming from judicial
office holder source system,
the data going into payment system.
So this is like a high level view,
then you have like within there you have
data coming in.
getting allocated across different APIs,
and even when we go into capabilities,
like what are the capabilities, absence,
working pattern management,
absence management, vacancy management.
So staying at a conceptual level,
and you can pick holes in it,
you can think of,
Yeah.
you did not think about this one because
you have just this vast knowledge of
working with the system day in, day out,
right?
Yeah.
And you can point out this will work for
tribunals,
but this will not work for codes,
for example.
So I think once I have, so this is really,
you know,
I'm still in the process of collecting
information,
so I'm able to build these views.
But once I have enough information,
I think it'll be really useful if I can
maybe, you know,
Yep.
run you through this and you can pick
holes in it or tell me,
and this is slightly better way of doing
it, if that's okay.
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
not not not a problem at all,
not a problem.
That's great,
and I can give you 20 minutes back and
you can enjoy a cup of tea.
Yeah, yeah.
See how many emails I've had since we've
been talking.
All right, Martin, cheers.
Thanks a lot for your time.
Cheers. Bye.